{
    "questions" : [
        {   "sections"      : "※ [1~3] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "52_1_img",
            "option_1"      : "①  ",
            "option_2"      : "②  ",
            "option_3"      : "③  ",
            "option_4"      : "④  ",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Where did you come from because you were sick?\nMan : I'm here because I have a stomachache.\nWoman : Then write your name and date of birth here and wait a moment.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  ",
            "score"         : "2",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [1~3] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "52_2_img",
            "option_1"      : "①  ",
            "option_2"      : "②  ",
            "option_3"      : "③  ",
            "option_4"      : "④  ",
            "detail"        : "Man : I'm done cleaning, can I help you wash the dishes?\nWoman : It's okay. I'm almost done, so sit down and get some rest.\nMan : Then let's have a cup of tea together after washing the dishes.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  ",
            "score"         : "2",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [1~3] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "52_3_img",
            "option_1"      : "①  ",
            "option_2"      : "②  ",
            "option_3"      : "③  ",
            "option_4"      : "④  ",
            "detail"        : "Man : Do you exercise often? According to the results of a survey by the Ministry of Culture, Sports and Tourism, the rate of Koreans participating in daily sports at least once a week has continued to increase since 2014. The most popular exercise was ‘walking’, followed by ‘mountain’, followed by ‘health’.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  ",
            "score"         : "2",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "4. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  찾아서 다행이네요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  천천히 잘 찾아봐요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  가방을 찾고 있는데요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  아무리 찾아도 없어서요.",
            "detail"        : "Man : What's wrong? Did you lose something.\nWoman : I don't know where my bag is.\nMan : Look for it slowly and well.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  천천히 잘 찾아봐요.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "5. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  점심 먹으러 갈래요?",
            "option_2"      : "②  점심시간이 언제예요?",
            "option_3"      : "③  식사 맛있게 하셨어요?",
            "option_4"      : "④  다른 데 가서 먹을까요?",
            "detail"        : "Man : There are a lot of people in the restaurant even though lunch time has passed.\nWoman : That's right. I have to wait a long time to eat.\nMan : Shall we go somewhere else to eat?",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  다른 데 가서 먹을까요?",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "6. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  다행히 잘 본 것 같아요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  생각보다 시험이 쉬웠어요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  떨지 말고 면접시험 잘 보세요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  열심히 준비했으니까 잘 될 거예요.",
            "detail"        : "Man : Mr. Sumi, how was your interview? Do you think you saw it well?\nWoman : I could have done well, but I was nervous, so I don't think I saw it well. \nMan : I've prepared hard, so it'll be fine.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  열심히 준비했으니까 잘 될 거예요.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "7. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  학교 홈페이지에 있던데요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  다음 학기에 신청하려고 해요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  이미 교환 학생 신청을 했어요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  벌써 학생 선발이 끝난 것 같아요.",
            "detail"        : "Man : Sumi, I heard that it's an exchange student application period until next week, are you going to apply?\nWoman : Is that so? How did you know?\nMan : It was on the school website.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  학교 홈페이지에 있던데요.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "8. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  화장품 좀 주문하려고 하는데요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  그럼 언제쯤 다시 받을 수 있을까요?",
            "option_3"      : "③  이 화장품 써 보니까 정말 좋은데요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  주문하신 날짜를 말씀해 주시겠어요?",
            "detail"        : "Woman : I ordered a lot of shoes. I got something different from the product I ordered.\nMan : Oh, I'm sorry, sir. Please send us the item and we will check it and send it back to you with the product you ordered.\nWoman : Then when can I get it again?",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  그럼 언제쯤 다시 받을 수 있을까요?",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [9~12]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 여자가 이어서 할행 동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "9. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  옷을 맡긴다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  코트를 산다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  세탁소에 간다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  우편물을 가져온다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Minsu, didn't you see my black coat you bought last time? \nMan : You left it at the laundry on Monday. Do you want me to find it for you?\nWoman : It's okay. I'll just go find it.\nMan : Then bring me some mail when you come in.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  세탁소에 간다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [9~12]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 여자가 이어서 할행 동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "10. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  안내 책자를 꺼낸다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  안내 책자를 받는다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  거래처 직원을 만난다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  상자를 책상 밑에 둔다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Hello? Minsu, I'm here to pick up the brochure from the office next door.\nMan : Oh, yes. I'm meeting a client's staff outside. I'm sorry, but could Mr. Sumi take it out of the box?\nWoman : Yes, I will. But where is the box.\nMan : I put it under my desk.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  안내 책자를 꺼낸다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [9~12]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 여자가 이어서 할행 동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "11. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  전등을 산다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  전등을 찾는다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  전등을 바꾼다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  전등을 가져온다",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Honey, I need to change the bathroom light. Man: Is that so? If you bought a light at home, bring it.\nWoman : Wait a minute. I'll find out where it is.\nMan : Tell me if you don't have it. I'll go buy.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  전등을 찾는다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [9~12]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 여자가 이어서 할행 동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "12. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  현황을 확인한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  부장님께 보고한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  인사과에 연락한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  지원자 명단을 본다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Manager, here is the list of applicants for overseas dispatch work. Would you like to take a look?\nMan : Oh, yes. What is the status of the application this time? Woman: I checked, but there are fewer applicants than I thought.\nMan : That's a big deal. Then contact the Human Resources Department to see if you can get additional support. I'll tell the former manager.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  인사과에 연락한다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [13~16] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "13. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  남자는 모임에 참석했다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  여자는 교통사고를 당했다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  여자는 어제 모임에 안 갔다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  남자는 얼마 전에 자동차를 샀다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Why didn't you come to the meeting yesterday? I was curious because I didn't hear from you.\nMan: Yes, I had a light car accident yesterday, so it took me a long time to deal with it.\nWoman : Really? It hasn't been long since I bought a car, so you must be upset. Are there any hurt places?\nMan : yeah. Fortunately, I'm not hurt.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  남자는 얼마 전에 자동차를 샀다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [13~16] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "14. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  이 세일 행사는 어제부터 시작했다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  모든 고객에게 양말을 선물로 준다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  선물을 받으려면 행사장으로 가야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  행사장에 가면 청바지를 만 원에 살 수 있다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman :  I would like to inform customers of shopping. At the event, jeans are on sale for 10,000 won. This event will only be held today, so we ask for your interest. Also, we will give socks to those who purchased more than 50,000 won at our shopping mall today. Please come to the customer center with your receipt. I hope you enjoy your shopping. Thank you. ",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  행사장에 가면 청바지를 만 원에 살 수 있다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [13~16] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "15. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  비는 오늘 밤에 그칠 것이다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  제주 지역에는 눈이 내릴 것이다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  모레는 기온이 떨어져 추워질 것이다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  내일 낮부터 전국적으로 비가 올 것이다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : This is the weather news. It's raining all over the country and there's a lot of rain in Jeju-do. This rain will mostly stop tomorrow morning, and it will gradually clear up from noon. In the morning of the day after tomorrow, the last cold will come and the whole country will be temporarily below zero. It's better to wear warm clothes when you go out. ",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  모레는 기온이 떨어져 추워질 것이다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [13~16] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "16. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  여자는 한 달 전에 다리를 다쳤다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  여자는 운동을 시작한 지 1년이 됐다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  여자는 지금 다른 나라에서 선수 생활을 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  여자는 처음에 팀 동료들과 사이가 안 좋았다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : Kim Mi-kyung, who is the first domestic volleyball player to go to the overseas stage. Please tell me how you have been in the past year.\nWoman : It was hard because I couldn't speak well at first. My teammates took good care of me, so I was able to adapt quickly. I was very frustrated when I couldn't go to the game for a month due to a leg injury in the beginning. After the return, I was happy that the team seemed to be a little supportive of winning.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  여자는 지금 다른 나라에서 선수 생활을 한다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [17~20] 다음을 듣고 남자의 중심 생각을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "17. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  결혼식을 하는 데 너무 많은 돈을 쓰면 안 된다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  결혼은 많은 사람들의 축하를 받으면서 해야 한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  결혼식 장소는 사람들이 찾아오기 편한 곳이 좋다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  결혼을 결정할 때 가족들의 의견을 고려해야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : You know my friend Minsu, right? They're getting married next month, and they're only calling a few close friends with their family. Isn't it good to invite a lot of people to a wedding?\nWoman : No. I think it's good to invite only people who are really close to you. There will be less cost burden. Small weddings like that are popular these days.\nMan : But it's a once-in-a-lifetime wedding, but I think I'll be sad if I make it too small.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  결혼은 많은 사람들의 축하를 받으면서 해야 한다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [17~20] 다음을 듣고 남자의 중심 생각을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "18. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  회사 일은 회사에서 끝내야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  소비자들의 의견을 잘 들어야 한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  일을 같이 하는 사람들과 잘 지내야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  발표 내용은 짧고 분명하게 하는 것이 좋다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : Mr. Sumi, did you make the release materials for tomorrow's new product?\nWoman : Yes, here it is. I've prepared the supplementary part you mentioned last time. Manager, could you take a look at it first? Man: Well, the content is too long and complicated. It is necessary to introduce the characteristics of the product briefly but clearly so that consumers can understand the product well.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  발표 내용은 짧고 분명하게 하는 것이 좋다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [17~20] 다음을 듣고 남자의 중심 생각을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "19. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  물건은 마트에서 사는 것이 싸다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  물건은 조금씩 사면 돈이 더 든다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  물건은 가격이 쌀 때 사 두어야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  물건은 필요할 때 조금씩 사는 게 좋다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Oh, this bread is on sale right now. It's only 10,000 won because it's tied up with 7 pieces. We buy too.\nMan : Well, I'm not sure if it's really cheap to sell like this at the mart.\nWoman : Why? It's expensive to buy one by one, but if you buy it like this, you can buy it cheaply. Man: I bought it in a bundle last time, but I couldn't eat it all and threw away half of it. Just buying and eating little by little when you want to eat is rather saving money.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  물건은 필요할 때 조금씩 사는 게 좋다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [17~20] 다음을 듣고 남자의 중심 생각을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "20. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  노래를 하는 사람은 정기적으로 앨범을 내야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  음악을 만들 때는 여러 악기를 사용하는 것이 좋다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  악기 없이 가수의 목소리만으로도 아름다운 음악이 된다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  혼자 노래하는 것보다 여럿이 모여 노래하는 것이 좋다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Among the songs on this regular album, songs that sang only with their voices without musical instruments are attracting attention. Is there any special reason why you made it like this?\nMan : Various instruments are good, but I think the singer's voice is the best instrument. If only the 4 of us get together, we can listen to the songs you mentioned to people anytime, anywhere, even if you don't have any musical instruments. I think I can make beautiful music just by the voices of singers like this.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  악기 없이 가수의 목소리만으로도 아름다운 음악이 된다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [21~22] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "21. 남자의 중심 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  우산이 홍보에 더 효과적이다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  우산을 만들 때 색깔이 중요하다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  수첩에 학교 이름이 들어가야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  수첩에 메모하는 습관을 길러야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Mr. Kim, what kind of school promotional supplies would be good this year? Shall we use a notebook with the name of our school like last year?\nMan : Well. I don't think the notebook is effective for school promotion because students don't use it well. The students didn't respond well last year. How about an umbrella this time? Umbrellas are used often, so if you engrave the name of the school on the umbrella, it will be good to inform the school.\nWoman : Yes, I got it. But what color should I do?\nMan : Well. Let's decide it with the other teachers next time.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  우산이 홍보에 더 효과적이다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [21~22] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "22. 들은 내용으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  올해 처음으로 홍보 용품을 만들었다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  홍보 용품으로 수첩을 제작할 예정이다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  여자는 남자에게 홍보 용품을 보여 줬다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  홍보 용품의 색깔은 다음에 정하기로 했다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Mr. Kim, what kind of school promotional supplies would be good this year? Shall we use a notebook with the name of our school like last year?\nMan : Well. I don't think the notebook is effective for school promotion because students don't use it well. The students didn't respond well last year. How about an umbrella this time? Umbrellas are used often, so if you engrave the name of the school on the umbrella, it will be good to inform the school.\nWoman : Yes, I got it. But what color should I do?\nMan : Well. Let's decide it with the other teachers next time.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  홍보 용품의 색깔은 다음에 정하기로 했다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [23~24] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "23. 남자의 중심 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  박물관 관람 예약을 하고 있다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  박물관의 위치를 안내하고 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  박물관 이용에 대해 문의하고 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  박물관에 사전 예약을 확인하고 있다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : Hello. Is it a children's museum I booked a ticket for 2 o'clock today. I was wondering if I could go in at 1 o'clock if I arrive early.\nWoman : Yes, hello? Then you can get a refund for the 2 o'clock ticket at the entrance and buy a new 1 o'clock ticket.\nMan : Yes, I got it. By the way, is there a place where I can eat in the museum?\nWoman : There is no separate restaurant. Instead, there is a family shelter on the 3rd floor. You can eat the food prepared there.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  박물관 이용에 대해 문의하고 있다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "24. 들은 내용으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  이 박물관의 관람권은 환불 받을 수 없다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  이 박물관에는 음식을 가지고 들어갈 수 없다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  이 박물관은 표를 예매하지 않아도 이용이 가능하다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  이 박물관에서는 자체적으로 식당을 운영하고 있다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : Hello. Is it a children's museum I booked a ticket for 2 o'clock today. I was wondering if I could go in at 1 o'clock if I arrive early.\nWoman : Yes, hello? Then you can get a refund for the 2 o'clock ticket at the entrance and buy a new 1 o'clock ticket.\nMan : Yes, I got it. By the way, is there a place where I can eat in the museum?\nWoman : There is no separate restaurant. Instead, there is a family shelter on the 3rd floor. You can eat the food prepared there.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  이 박물관은 표를 예매하지 않아도 이용이 가능하다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "25. 남자의 중심 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  기업은 시민 영웅을 채용해야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  기업은 사회에 도움이 되는 일에 앞장서야 한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  시민 영웅은 사회를 위해 자신을 희생해야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  언론은 숨어 있는 시민 영웅을 찾아 알려야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : The boss is doing a lot of great work, such as helping neighbors in need and supporting poor students. Recently, I heard that you made the 'Citizen Hero Award'. What award is that?\nMan : Yes, there are people around us who are unknown but are exemplary in society. I'm going to find such people and give them a prize. If the winner does not want to, the awards ceremony will proceed quietly without disclosing to the press. In the meantime, I found a total of 31 citizen heroes and gave them awards and prizes. There was also a person who donated the prize money again for their neighbors. There was also a college student award who rescued a child at the fire site, and we hired him after graduation. I think it is the responsibility of the company to return the profits received from society back to society.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  기업은 사회에 도움이 되는 일에 앞장서야 한다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "26. 들은 내용으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  이 기업에 입사한 수상자가 있다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  이 상은 시상식을 따로 하지 않는다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  이 남자는 최근에 시민 영웅상을 받았다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  이 상은 시민들이 기부금을 모아 만들었다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : The boss is doing a lot of great work, such as helping neighbors in need and supporting poor students. Recently, I heard that you made the 'Citizen Hero Award'. What award is that?\nMan : Yes, there are people around us who are unknown but are exemplary in society. I'm going to find such people and give them a prize. If the winner does not want to, the awards ceremony will proceed quietly without disclosing to the press. In the meantime, I found a total of 31 citizen heroes and gave them awards and prizes. There was also a person who donated the prize money again for their neighbors. There was also a college student award who rescued a child at the fire site, and we hired him after graduation. I think it is the responsibility of the company to return the profits received from society back to society.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  이 기업에 입사한 수상자가 있다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        }
    ]
}
